Hardware, innovation, money and power
collide in Silicon Valley and beyond.
This is Bloomberg Technology with
Caroline Hyde and Ed Ludlow.
I from New York and San francisco.
This is Bloomberg Technology.
Coming up, netflix out a record.
The king of streaming surpasses Wall
Street's expectations on every major
financial metric.
Plus, after iPhone sales stall in a
major market overseas, a sign of
success.
And why Tesla is in the crosshairs of a
federal agencies investigation.
And yeah, let's get right to Netflix.
And this.
This is the stock, right?
You can see on the screen the story on
track for its biggest jump since January
of this year, trading at a record high
overall.
And subscribers beat revenue beat.
And we always talk about earnings in the
context of beating expectations
numerically on metrics.
But I think we both agree right Karowe
that the story was different to what we
were expecting a slowdown in streaming?
No, actually, things seem to be okay for
Netflix.
I think there's a lot to get into about
what's happening with the consumer's
attitude towards streaming platforms and
how we're watching content right now.
Yeah, the co-CEO and sounding upbeat.
Ted Sarandos really talking about how
the company beat those expectations, but
also what you can expect in 2025.
Take a listen.
Let's start with, you know, looking into
2025, we're feeling really good about
the business.
We had a plan to re accelerate growth
and we delivered on that plan.
You can see that in our 2024 financials,
we expect to deliver 15% revenue growth
and six percentage points of operating
margin improvement and engagement, which
we view as our best proxy for member
happiness.
Because when people watch more, they
stick around longer.
So that's retention.
Felix Gillette joins us.
And Felix, it really was a case of even
without the stellar slate they have
coming up in fourth quarter.
They managed to really build on that.
5 million subscribers for the third.
Yeah, I think it was better than
everyone expected.
I think it's particularly impressive
because you have to remember this is the
year following the dual strikes in
Hollywood.
So there's this huge production
slowdown.
At the time everyone was speculating
like, well, there's not enough new
things to watch.
Why would people keep subscribing to
these streaming services, including
Netflix?
There's going to be a lot of churn, a
lot of cancellations.
And yet, in spite of that, a year later,
you know, Netflix adds another 5 million
subscribers.
This quarter is up to 282 plus million
across the globe.
So, yeah, it's a very strong order for
Netflix.
And like Sarandos said, they have an
even better slate, I think you could
argue, coming up next quarter and next
year.
So he talks about this interesting
metric, which is I think he called it
engagement, right?
Felix And misdirect.
So let's bring Felix's shot back up
because I don't think he's had much time
to watch Netflix.
He's been too busy reading the piles of
books either side of his shoulder.
But there was a time when Netflix said,
Stop judging us on subscriber growth.
Just look at our financial metrics.
Now they say, don't judge us on
financial metrics.
We really want to talk about this
engagement number.
What does it mean and where is it going?
I think when you look at the engagement
number, part of that is where is their
future growth going to come from?
And a lot of that is advertising, right?
They said yesterday, you know, we're not
where we're at, where we want to be at
in terms of advertising revenue, but
we're investing in technology and we're
investing in better inventory.
And what that means is investing in
better live programming.
And they just have a ton of stuff coming
down the pipeline.
Wrestling, 3 hours of live wrestling a
week.
They're going to have NFL games.
They're doing more comedy live specials.
Last week at our conference in L.A.,
they announced they're going to do this
live variety show.
And I think that's going to be very
appealing to advertisers once they get a
certain crucial number of viewers there.
And I think that's where the engagement
comes from.
And I think that's what they're really
excited about now.
But I think you can't separate that from
their ambitions in advertising.
Well, maybe he's kind of excited about
the next edition of Wednesday because I
can spot thing lurking behind your right
shoulder at the moment.
Yes.
Amazing.
Felix to that we thank you so much at.
Let's get some more data from Brandon
Katz.
He's the senior entertainment industry
strategist at Parrot Analytics.
And there's actually a data point that
you point to which I find fascinating,
and that is Netflix's share in corporate
demand.
Explain that metric and why you think it
makes Netflix a leader.
So corporate demand share really looks
at all the original programming that a
company creates, and it helps value
their viability in the current media
market and potentially the value of that
content on the opening market should
they ever want to license it for the
first time ever.
Netflix has leapfrogged a legacy media
company by beating NBCUniversal, and we
have to remember NBC Universal's
programming dates back to the 1940s with
NBC, whereas Netflix has only been an
original programmer for about 12 years.
So the fact that their library has grown
this significantly this quickly is a
major testament to the amassed content
that they have built.
They have had to spend a lot on that
content.
And the point is now whether they have
to spend a lot on live content on sports
to really drum up this advertising
prowess that actually Amazon seems to
have nailed in many ways.
Yeah.
And with Amazon expanding its ad tier
next year to five additional markets,
the pressure is on Netflix to grow this
advertising tier.
It's been a slow but steady first two
years.
But what's really concerning is that
Netflix is you can average revenue per
user has dropped for two straight
quarters because of that ad tier growth.
So it's a little bit of a give and take.
I would not be surprised if with the
addition of WWE and NFL games, we see a
increase in the price for the ad
supported tier in 2025 some time.
What about price point of the service
more broadly, many anticipating that we
could get some price hikes.
In fact, they just enacted some today.
Absolutely.
We're getting international price hikes.
I would not be surprised if another
youcan't price hike is around the
corner, particularly off the back of
their extremely strong anticipated Q4
content slate.
And as they mentioned, the production
logjam is starting to normalize
following the strike.
So we could probably expect a little bit
more volume in terms of new originals in
2025, which also bolsters their case in
raising prices yet again.
So consumers maybe watch that wallet a
little bit more.
Okay.
If you're just joining us here on
Bloomberg Technology, Netflix shares are
up more than 10%, the biggest jump since
January, but they're trading at their
highest level ever on record.
And I think a big part of that is, is
there is still subscriber growth and
brand.
And that was the story we were kind of
considering with this slowdown.
You mentioned a moment ago the live
events.
I want to go deeper into that.
How much of a feature this will be of
the platform going forward?
Yeah.
Live events has not worked seamlessly
for any streaming platform consistently.
It's always been simulcast on these
legacy media distribution networks and
their streaming services.
So Netflix is really trying to break new
ground by making live entertainment on a
streaming only service work.
And it is certainly a huge point of
focus for them moving forward to
supercharge their ad tier.
And I think then focusing the first ten
years of their kind of original content
development around building out the back
end by licensing other content and
building up a massive library is the
right way to go about it.
I think they're well positioned to dive
deeper into sports because of it now.
Nice.
We got some bridgerton up on the screen.
That's a household favor for us.
What do you make of management?
We're kind of in deeper into this period
where you have the co-CEO structure.
You think they're doing a good job?
I think they're doing a fantastic job.
And I think Greg Peters is one of the
only Hollywood media executives with
actual coding and software experience.
And I think as we dive into an even more
digital future, trying to capture Gen Z
retention and Gen Alpha's attention, who
are digital natives, it's going to be
very, very, very important to understand
how the tech works and what the consumer
experience on that tech is actually
like, and Netflix is taking a step
forward with that.
Yeah, I mean, they've really beefed out
the ability to carry live events.
I mean, we all think back to the Love is
Blind disaster.
When they tried to carry that live and
we saw the demand just to get down.
But from that, just reflect a little bit
on ultimately where else Gen Z
millennials are going because yes, you
cite the old school that they've
overtaken in terms of just sheer volume
of content, but people are spending that
time on Tik Tok on YouTube.
How are they matching up in terms of
addiction there?
The concern with Netflix is that it's a
pure play, traditional entertainment
service that is focused on film and TV
and yet video games, short form media
via the creator economy and other new
media are driving growth in the
entertainment ecosystem as film and TV
endure a painful contract contraction.
Yes, Netflix is building out a suite of
video games, but we've had no material
updates on its impact as they try to
build an added value in-house bundle
that goes beyond just traditional film
and TV.
So that's why I think perhaps Netflix is
slightly overvalued at the moment, even
as they clearly dominate in the
traditional entertainment lane.
I've got we got to jump in on that.
That gaming side of the equation and the
lackluster, I mean, are they going to
continue down the gaming path?
Ed wants to know.
The reports are that they are developing
a triple-A game, which is what I think
gamers most associate with those big
classic console games.
Now, the success or failure of that will
certainly say a lot about the health and
longevity of their video game efforts.
Now, do they need it to succeed?
Not in the interim, but moving forward?
Long term, yes, I think they need to
branch out beyond just film and
television to create a stickier bundle
that solves for multiple consumer pain
points.
Brendon Katz, senior entertainment
industry strategist at Paradigm.
It's great to have you back here on
Bloomberg Technology.
Thank you so much.
Coming up, Apple sees unexpected demand
in China.
We speak about that and the broader tech
market with Angelo Cook-Off of Edward
Jones.
That conversation is coming up.
This is Bloomberg Technology.
The renaissance of growth has begun for
Apple with iPhone 16.
I think China, look, that was the
biggest issue.
That was a headwind.
Now it's a tailwind.
They have mojo going into the next, I
think, 6 to 9 months.
And that's why I look why the bears, if
you fire in a crowded theater for the
last month, but I think they go back
into hibernation mode in our opinion.
I was a very colorful Dan Ives of
Wedbush Securities.
On Apple's China turnaround.
Does the data provide a counterpoint?
Research says iPhone 16 sales so 20% in
the country in its first three weeks.
For more, let's bring in Bloomberg's
Mark Gurman.
Now, when we've discussed some third
party data, it's usually been negative.
And then Apple with actual data in the
earnings context has proven it wrong.
This is counterpoint research data.
That is a surprise and it's a positive
surprise.
What does it tell us about iPhone six in
that market?
Barely think it tells us anything new.
I think it tells us that the first three
weeks of iPhone sales, as they usually
are, were pretty hot.
Right.
The issue was never the opening month of
the device.
The issue was over the long term.
Right.
Three, six, nine months to 12 months for
the full cycle of that device.
I think some analysts have been a little
irrational or irresponsible in their
commentary on the iPhone 16 over the
last several months.
Some analysts have gone as far as
claiming that this is going to create a
supercycle, something we haven't seen
since the iPhone first launched on China
mobile with bigger screens a decade ago.
Right.
They've been saying that Apple
intelligence is something that is going
to drive a supercycle, despite the fact
that Apple intelligence is not available
in China.
Right.
So you can't necessarily have it both
ways.
You can't say that it's going to create
a supercycle in China.
Well, A.I.
is not available in China, right?
I'm not entirely surprised.
The iPhone 16 is doing well in the
region.
There's a lot of pent up demand.
There's a lot of people in China who
didn't upgrade the prior two years, the
iPhone 14 Pro and the iPhone 15 pro.
The iPhone six has some nice
improvements.
Right.
I think the camera control interface is
excellent.
Right.
I think the speed improvements in the
battery life improvements are really
nice touches.
I've enjoyed those personally.
So I think it's a good upgrade for
people who haven't bought a new iPhone
in the past few years, so I'm not
entirely surprised.
And typically, even when the data is
negative, right, I typically come on
here and say is we're not going to know
the truth until Apple earnings.
Right.
That's the case even when it's positive.
And so at the end of this month, we'll
get a better idea of how accurate this
information is.
Mark, next time we are bringing you and
Dan, I've supercycle man on together for
some fighting talk.
We love it today but more broadly, what
do you think that there is not bits to
love with an iPhone six.
The bit that I'm just so questioning is
the key element.
You've told this story again and again
on your own X platform in particular.
Why?
Who are they going to partner with in
China?
How are they going to really reap the
benefits of the artificial intelligence?
Yeah.
So there's two components really to the
API push in the iPhone, right?
There's the in-house large language
models and generative A.I.
features.
Those are using an Apple model.
Those are running on Apple servers.
And then there is the third party
component that's integrated into Siri
and other parts of the operating system
in the U.S.
They're using so far starting in
December.
And they're also planning to integrate
Google Gemini and to open it up to other
LMS in the future.
So you have an array of choices in
China.
Most of those providers in the U.S.
are not available, so they're going to
have to partner with local entities.
Baidu being one option.
Obviously, you have Tencent, obviously
you have different bespoke labs in the
region.
But the other component is how is Apple
going to get approval from the Chinese
government to use their server
infrastructure to power their in-house
generative A.I.
models, which are in fact the bigger
deal, right, for Apple intelligence
notification summaries, writing tools,
image Generation Z emojis to create your
own emojis, right?
At least for iCloud, they have to use a
partner right in China with government
affiliation.
And so they may end up having to do
something similar if they want to get
Apple intelligence working in China.
Right.
And China is one of two major markets,
the other being the European Union,
where the A.I.
features are not available on the
iPhone.
And there's no clear release date for
when that will happen.
And I don't anticipate that happening
for at least a year.
Nice.
Bloomberg's Mark Gurman.
Keep your eyes peeled for his power on
news that this weekend in Korea as we're
showing, clearly Apple and its gains are
a factor in the market this Friday.
They are.
Let's talk about that, about the broader
market with Angelo Cephas, his senior
investment strategist over at Edward
Jones.
And just let's dwell on Apple for a
moment and what it signals that we got
UK retail data out today that said it
was buoyed by things like the Apple
iPhone but also Google's pixel as well.
How important is consumer to Apple right
now and how resilient is it?
Yeah, I think today's strength in
Mega-cap tech, including Apple, is
really a reminder not to dismiss
technology.
Technology actually remains a bright
spot.
The consumer clearly has been the main
driver for not only some of these
technology names, but for really the
broader economy and the bull markets
thesis.
And we keep getting good news on that
front.
Economic surprises are turning positive.
Just retail sales this week expressed
some strength and resilience.
So the economy is nowhere near
recession, especially in the U.S.
The same applies to abroad.
Now, China is a complicated story, to
say the least.
But at the same time, there's some signs
of bottom in that also feeds into the
Apple story.
We've had pledges from policymakers to
support growth.
Many questions remain.
What's going to actually be the lever?
But at least from a sentiment investor
sentiment perspective seems like the
worst is behind us.
Angelo, when you talk about profitable
tack, historically, it's like in the
context of having amazing balance sheet
entrenched market position.
But here on Bloomberg Technology, we
talk about innovation.
That's what Mark was reporting on, which
is the more important factor to the
investor.
I think it's both.
But you have that long, long term
secular thesis.
There's a long runway for growth,
especially on artificial intelligence.
But also you have the reality of market
swings and rotations have happened
because of the industry backdrop in the
more near-term and both moderate based
on your time horizon.
Think about the current backdrop.
We have an economy that is still growing
at a very solid pace.
Corporate profits are on the rise and at
the same time, interest rates are moving
lower.
And that backdrop provides a little more
tailwinds for areas of the market that
have been really left behind over the
past 18 months.
The big cap technology companies,
they're in a net cash position.
They have more cash than debt.
So they've been benefiting from the rise
in interest rates.
Right.
And other areas have been hit.
On the flip side, as interest rates move
lower.
You are seeing really that broadening
start to play out.
Angela, it's been great having some time
with you.
Thank you very much indeed.
Talking all through the valuation story,
Angelo Krakoff is senior investment
strategist at Edward Jones.
Now we just want to keep a close eye on
some other stocks that are on the move
at the moment.
And we're looking at American Express
coming up by 3.8% have been off by more
than 5%.
We are getting a refocusing in terms of
its revenue forecast, maybe its 9%
growth for the year rather than up to 9
to 11%.
But we did speak to the CEO, Stephen
Squeri, and he's been telling us
something by television that we've had
ten consecutive quarters of record
revenue.
And really good quarter.
We beat our own expectations.
The Street to we're raising guidance
when it comes to earnings per share.
We'll see how the stock continues
perform.
Remember, it has been Nair's records as
well.
Coming up, why some strategists are
urging caution for those investing
billions into volatile Chinese stock
ETFs.
This is Bloomberg Technology.
Let's turn to China now.
Investors are learning that Chinese
stock ETFs and now among the most risky,
the performance over the long haul has
made some of the biggest wealth
destroyers among US ETFs.
It's about to be reported on this.
And time and time again, you've come on
to tell us about how China is faring in
the macro context.
And we're looking at K Webb in
particular.
It's got all of our Chinese tech names
that are listed here.
It's been painful, very painful.
So this is a story about how market
timing is tough, but especially tougher
for other sectors, especially China.
So we looked at all ETF set an aim of
above 1 billion and we basically
subtracted assets and net inflows
because net inflows is less than the
assets.
It means investors lost money over their
lifetime.
And among that list, Chinese ETFs were
at the top, and Cathie Wood's ARK funds
a couple of them.
So back to Chinese ETF, you mentioned
Quip over its inception since 2013,
investors ploughed in 12 billion, but
its assets right now is just 6.9
billion.
So that's a valuation gap of 5 billion.
And after K12, it is Cathie Wood's
flagship ARK fund that also lost
investors money.
For context, you look at SPI, which is
the biggest and most liquid ETF
investors pulled in 160 billion.
Right now it's around 700 billion.
So you see that investors were rewarded
there.
So it's really hard for the Chinese
ETFs.
Is about.
You said timing The market is hard.
But more recently, China stimulus.
And then on the regulatory side, take
video games, for example, signals that
policy might support some of those
names.
So now you're asking, okay, well, what's
the trajectory from here?
Exactly.
So I want to bring it back to 2021.
So Caleb saw fantastic inflows, then 7.4
billion.
That's when investors were kind of
optimistic that China will see a rebound
from the doldrums of the pandemic.
But also that year to year point, we saw
a deepening housing crisis.
We saw some industries being really
cracked down on and we saw that ETF
tumble 52%.
Fast forward to today.
We saw a massive stimulus blitz in three
weeks.
We saw a lot of indexes tracking Chinese
stocks rise 40%.
And we saw investors also plowing
billions into the Chinese ETFs,
including Kay Webb.
But they're now taking a step back.
Chinese shares are kind of faltering.
We're seeing that rally kind of fizzle.
So it raises the question, will we see
something like that again?
And China is really just it's a very
vulnerable vehicle.
It's very volatile.
So it's really one thing that investors
should think about when they invest in
those kind of ETFs.
Bloomberg's Isabel is one of the best
read stories today on the Bloomberg
terminal and dot com and that's why we
wanted you on the program.
Thank you very much indeed.
Now coming up here on Bloomberg
Technology, the future of American made
semiconductor chips.
Michelle Guida from the Crack Institute
of Tech Diplomacy at Purdue University
is here.
We also have Bloomberg's best and
brightest on the week that was in semis.
This is Bloomberg Technology.
Welcome back to Bloomberg Technology.
I'm Caroline Hyde in New York and I met
Ivo in San Francisco to check on these
markets because we had a volatile one.
Let's put it because the Nasdaq has been
pushed around by those chip names that
we're going to dig into in a moment.
We're currently still holding on ground
for 10% for the last five trading days,
telling us had a nice little five day
performance.
Crypto.
Move it on and have a look at what's
happened with MicroStrategy Benchmark.
Also the analyst they're raising the
price target but MicroStrategy, one of
the biggest points contributors to the
Nasdaq 100 today.
Netflix I mean the standout of the day
up 10%.
Record high, 5 million subscribers being
added in the previous quarter, and
they're going to eclipse that in the
fiscal fourth quarter and last year.
Look at ASML.
This is a recovery, maybe a buy the dip
story on this particular day.
We're up just 3% on the US listed and
and European listed.
I'm currently looking at the dnb one's
up some 3%.
It has been sold off 14% over the course
of the week.
We know why the war is on orders.
The war is on everything else.
Bar, A.I.
chip equipment.
Basically what we got in the chip
sector.
Let me take you on a journey over just
five days.
There's been seismic shifts in
semiconductor sentiment.
It all started with chip equipment maker
ASML, surprising with early release of
results, cutting its outlook and
injecting growth concerns.
But by week's end, TSMC CHIP contract
manufacturers the world settled nerves,
boosting sales growth predictions and
spending plans, signaling the air
investment cycle might be okay.
And Vedere is flirting with some new
record highs.
Bloomberg's Ian King, who leads
semiconductor coverage, is here with us.
And that's the point.
The eye of the semiconductor industry is
okay.
Everything else, I think we're still a
little bit worried about.
Yeah, no, that's absolutely right.
The biggest concern, because that's
where all the money has been poured into
is is this high demand that we've seen
all these huge orders for Nvidia
supported.
Is this something that can continue?
And we got evidence that yes, that's the
case, at least for now.
What investors turn their attention to
is that other areas, automotive,
industrial PC, maybe not so good.
Let's dwell on the automotive part
though, in because you had a great story
with Mackenzie Hawkins talking about how
wall speed is going to be getting money
from the likes of Apollo, going to be
expanding its manufacturing for EV
chips.
So why that?
Yeah, I mean, this this is the little
tech company that apparently now can.
And there were existential concerns
about this company.
Literally, it was running out of money.
It's had a lot of problems bringing
online some new manufacturing.
And, you know, there were a lot of notes
out there, a lot of analysts saying
maybe this company needs to be bought,
it needs to go away, needs something.
Now, it got this, you know, massive
injection into its balance sheet, which
should allow it to emerge from this dark
place that it's been in.
Huge share reaction to that that that
we've obviously seen this week.
But still, the stock market does not
love this company.
The funny thing is, is the earnings
season is kind of back again.
And to go to your first point on the
everything else part, Texas Instruments
is kind of up first.
It's the everything Chip's name.
Just to explain that and why you'll be
paying close attention.
Yeah, we're going to have them reporting
on Tuesday.
And like you said, they are everything
else, automotive, industrial, of their
two biggest markets.
They make analog and embedded
processors.
These markets haven't been great.
You know, a lot of the typical sort of
everybody in everybody out cycle of PC
and smartphone, that kind of trend has
kind of gone away.
And we've seen all of these individual
markets moving in different ways.
Texas Instruments has been really
struggling.
And how they might change the narrative
is is if they give us any
hope.
I'm kind of comments about what's coming
in the future that says maybe we're
through the worst.
That could be a positive.
But if you actually look at the numbers,
we're still struggling.
The index in King Reste, up we go again
next week.
Thank you very much, Kara.
Look, we've got to talk now about how
politics plays its role as well, the
intersection of technology and politics,
a major decision facing whoever, of
course, wins the White House next month,
how to regulate US chip industry in
particular, to stay ahead of global
competition.
Let's dig into that.
Michelle Greta, she's the CEO of Hatch
Institute for Tech Diplomacy at Purdue
University.
Michel, the context with which we talk
about Invidious and some of the other
key players is the limitations of
selling into China.
That was a key story for small, for
example, going forward.
Is that going to perpetuate itself?
Caroline, You're right.
Context is really important here.
And when you think about it, it's just
reflective of the new paradigm that
we're in, in which tech has to do very
much with the future of American
prosperity and American national
security.
So just as we have to scrutinize which
countries we're sending F-35s to.
We also have to scrutinize where we're
sending our most advanced chips to which
also power our F-35s.
And these aren't hairdryers that we're
talking about.
And why we have to look at this is
ultimately it comes down to trust.
Do we trust the companies?
Do we trust the countries that we're
going to be sending our in video chips
and our most advanced critical
technology to with the understanding
that it's not going to end up in the
hands of some of our adversaries, like
Russia, like China and the People's
Liberation Army.
Do you have a clear sense of any benefit
being derived from current and existing
policy on semiconductors for the United
States?
Look, we've taken measures over the
course of a couple of administrations
now to make sure that we're preventing
our most critical technology from going
to our adversaries and specifically
China.
But this is why tech diplomacy is also
really important.
When I was assistant secretary of state,
I was traveling all across the world.
And the number one thing that you hear
from our allies and partners is that
they want U.S.
private sector investment.
Well, it's really hard to do that when
you have Chinese technology, untrusted
technology embedded into your government
infrastructure and across your country.
And so you want to make sure that you're
using trusted technology.
If you look at the U.S.
and 12 of our closest Democratic
partners, we make up 12 at almost two
thirds of global GDP.
China, Russia, Iran.
Venezuela is less than 20% of GDP.
So you want to be a part of the big
network.
There's a lot of financial opportunity,
diplomatic opportunity in that.
And so we've started to, through
American policy, implement the right
policies around semiconductors to make
sure that we are helping the partners in
that trusted network and not in the
untrusted network.
Michel.
Earlier this week, Bloomberg's editor in
chief, John Micklethwait, spoke to
former President Trump and very directly
tried to get a sense of what his policy
will be with regards to China.
Let's listen to his comments.
But the reason they're doing it now is
they're not going to do it afterwards.
Okay.
Since, you know, so they're doing it
now.
They want to do it.
And I look at it now.
I had a very
good relationship with president.
She had a very good relationship with
Putin and a very good relationship with
Kim Jong un, who is a nuclear force that
you won't even believe.
President Trump discussed his good
relationship with Xi, but I think many
agree that we didn't get an
understanding of whether he would
continue with the existing stance of
sort of export control on leading edge
Chip.
What is your expectation if President
Trump were to take office in November or
in January of next year?
But remember, export controls on
critical technology from China began
under President Trump and specifically
with Huawei.
This is with regards to 5G.
While we ultimately lost $30 billion in
annual revenue because the United States
under President Trump worked with 60
countries and 200 telecommunications
companies to only use trusted vendors in
5G, and that did not include Huawei.
We've seen those export controls
continue now under the Biden
administration.
It's been on chips lately, but I think
you can start to see this is American
foreign policy.
Now, not only that, the Congress is very
bipartisan.
Just a couple of days ago, the China
Select Committee called for putting more
Chinese companies on the entity list.
This is Huawei's network of clandestine
companies, which American companies are
sending semiconductor manufacturing
equipment.
So this is a very bipartisan thing, and
we should expect it to continue.
And yet, Michel, companies still want to
access the Chinese consumer.
Apple still wants to build its phones
there, still wants to access the
consumer that NVIDIA still wants to sell
its less sophisticated chips over to
China, too.
What is a CEO to do?
What does Jensen Huang or Tim Cook to do
in that situation?
Well, it's really interesting, actually.
It was a Bloomberg reporter just a
couple of weeks ago, had asked Jensen
Huang his take on the China export
controls, and he said he had to defer
policymaking to the United States.
Unfortunately, in the world that we live
in when it comes to American national
security, that's not anything that any
CEO of a critical tech company can
defer.
We all have to be in this together and
in what's ultimately a technology race.
American CEOs and tech CEOs in
particular need to make sure that we are
advancing our tech competitiveness.
At the same time, we're not giving that
technology to our adversaries who are
dedicated to our demise.
So there's a very big leadership role
for CEOs.
Michelle Wieder, fantastic to have some
time with you.
Thank you.
CEO of the Institute for Tech Diplomacy
at Purdue University.
Coming up, why Tesla driverless car
program is the target for federal
investigators.
This is Bloomberg Technology.
That's optimistic goals.
Okay.
Last week's Tesla Robotaxi event was so
underwhelming that Wall Street is
questioning the stock's premium
valuation.
The so-called ROBOTAXI has been crucial
to keeping Tesla's stock at Lofty
Heights.
It's trading at around 75 times forward
earnings on hopes that A.I.
will recreate the auto industry through
Musk's vision.
Here's a look at the stock since the
event.
The next catalyst to watch is, of
course, third quarter results, for which
I will be glued to my desk along with
everyone else around the world.
Karoline, will you be?
Of course.
What brutal chore.
Meanwhile, we've got to be glued to
something else, said the National
Highway Traffic Safety Administration.
It's investigating Tesla's powerful
automation system.
They market it as full self-driving and
it's following concerns it is defective.
After a series of crashes, one which
resulted in a fatality.
Bloomberg's Craig Trudel relentless on
this.
Craig This is to do with the weather,
right?
Yeah, this is at least sort of the
grounds for the investigation that is
sort of narrowly looking at the issue of
of, you know, when Teslas are being
operated on FSD and in in an environment
where visibility isn't great.
So think of like foggy conditions.
But I would point out that it's not
necessarily the case that these
investigations would sort of stay in
that narrow scope where we've seen a
precedent just with autopilot, this sort
of standard driver assistance system
that you get when you buy a Tesla that
we saw in its open in an investigation
after multiple crashes involving police
cars or fire trucks.
And that investigation led to a much
broader recall where Tesla sort of, you
know, came around to this idea that, you
know, what next.
You're right.
We will sort of, you know, find that
there's a defect with our system, that
people aren't paying enough attention
while they use it.
And we'll we'll do a remedy to try and
address that.
Craig, as you note, because you're one
of the editors of my reporting about
Tesla, I'm an FSD user, and actually
I've posted on quite a lot about using
it in foggy conditions and some of the
bizarre happenings when using the
technology.
One question that I have and many have
is about this probe and how it's
different from prior probes and why
actually this time around it may have
teeth, so to speak.
Whereas, you know, in the past we
haven't seen much happen after the
probe.
Yeah, I think it's interesting.
These these defect investigations tend
to take quite a bit of time.
I mentioned the autopilot one.
It took, you know, I think several years
really for for anything to really come
of that.
And, you know, so so that is one thing
to note, that it's a tends to move at a
speed that is not sort of befitting of
our, you know, modern sort of daily
drumbeat of headlines.
Age.
I do think that what's interesting here
is that, you know, just with that that
autopilot investigation that
precipitated a recall, Tesla was able to
address that with an over-the-air
software update, or at least they tried
to do so.
And it's has gone back and said, you
know what, We're not sure that that went
far enough.
So I think when you ask about, you know,
whether or not this could have teeth, I
think the real question here, if you're
a Tesla investor, is, you know, will
Nitze get to the point where they say,
you know what, Tesla, we think that you
don't have sufficient hardware to for
people to be able to use these systems
safely.
And do you need to do more for, you
know, monitoring drivers better and
install equipment to do that?
Do you need to put in sensors to handle
these these poor visibility conditions
that would cost Tesla some real money?
And does that question the pace, which
is slower than rivals of a cyber cab or
a fully independently driving car that
we already see on the streets of Waymo?
Yeah, I think it's key here that, you
know, it's a I think this is going to
have to, you know, have some say in
Tesla following through on what Musk
said last week about being able to offer
a version of FSD that doesn't have to be
supervised, at least in certain states.
You know, Musk mentioned that in Texas
and California.
You know, it's it just strikes me as
hard to sort of take him at his word
that that timeline can possibly be
achieved when we're seeing evidence, you
know, year after year of of crashes
involving people using these systems
and, you know, them not necessarily, you
know, being safe enough to to
regulator's liking.
MUSK Ambitious timelines.
Right now we thank you and.
Yeah, plenty more news in today's
talking tech.
And first stop.
What's the story?
Japanese software developer Fuji Soft is
sticking with taken off for its shares
despite receiving a higher bid from Bain
Capital.
This is Fuji.
Soft Executives has shown doubt about
the feasibility of Bain's goal of taking
the company private.
We'll track that one.
Plus, Google's moving the team behind
its Gemini AI assistant app to its
DeepMind research lab.
It's part of a plan to consolidate the
company's sprawling AI structure.
And Verizon will buy $1 billion worth of
US cellular spectrum licenses for its
core business.
US cellular controls, one of the largest
tower businesses in the United States.
All right.
Coming up on the program, we've got a
deeper look at what's next for Netflix.
Plenty more to discuss after earnings.
This is Bloomberg Technology.
Welcome back to Bloomberg Technology.
Let's take a look at where Netflix is at
right now.
Earnings just beating investor
expectations.
The stock is up ten and a half percent.
Biggest jump since January of this year
and the stock is trading at all time
highs.
Let's go in-house.
Let's bring in geeta ranganathan,
bloomberg intelligence and Geeta, your
research you published this morning.
We'll get right to it.
You look at the subscriber gains, that
was a surprise.
But you also judging Netflix on its
margins.
And it's really interesting to me
because Netflix for ages was like stop
obsessing over subscribers.
Judge us on our financial metrics.
Well, you are.
Y
yeah, absolutely.
And so, you know, it was really a broad
based very, very good report, as you
just pointed out.
And yes, this has shifted now from being
just principally a subscriber story to
now more of an all rounded kind of
financial story as well.
So good topline revenue growth, but more
importantly, that topline revenue growth
kind of translating into very, very
solid bottom line growth, very solid
profitability.
And we saw that yesterday in Netflix,
almost flirting with 30% operating
margin in the third quarter.
And then look at their guidance.
When we came into 2024, they were
expecting or they were guiding margins
at about 22%.
Yesterday, they lifted it again from 24,
25, 26 and now 27% operating margins.
And again, the target that they set for
2025 looks really, really conservative
to us.
But this is basically this goes back to
the age old question of us always
asking, you know, does streaming
economics really do they make sense?
Can this model be as good as the
original traditional TV model?
And Netflix has proven to us that it can
be done.
What's interesting, though, is the
previous chart we just showed is strong
subscribers, but still a slowing growth
trajectory.
And I'm interested by perhaps Latin
America seeing no growth in subscribers.
Why is that happening?
Where is it happening?
Yes.
So, you know, it is a little bit of up
and down.
So they did talk about Latin America
being a little bit of a timing issue.
They're actually now continuing to see
good growth starting in the in the
calendar fourth quarter.
But, you know, there are mature markets
and there are markets where there is
going to be a lot of growth.
So if you kind of just look at it as us
versus rest of the world, 80% of
subscriber growth comes from the rest of
the world.
So the US obviously is the most mature
market, but there still are pockets
across the world.
Karoline, whether you're looking at Asia
Pacific or India.
India, for instance, last quarter for
them was one of their most, you know,
highest growing markets in terms of
number of new subscribers as well as in
terms of revenue growth.
So they do have pockets all across the
world, whether it's in Eastern Europe,
whether it's in Asia-Pacific, where they
are going to try and reinvigorate
subscriber growth.
And those are going to be their biggest
areas of opportunity going forward.
Geyser Bloomberg Intelligence House Call
Is Netflix still the number one streamer
and will it always be the number one
streamer?
I think so, Ed.
I mean, they definitely have one.
The streaming wars right now as we as we
kind of look at it way ahead of
everybody else, way ahead of the
competition, not just in terms of
subscriber numbers, even if you look at
them in terms of engagement.
Remember, they are just a smidge behind
YouTube.
And YouTube has over 2 billion viewers
across the world.
It's a free service, right?
And you're looking at Netflix where, you
know, it's a paying subscription
service, a little bit of a different
model, but they still have almost close
to 10% of viewing time in the US, which
is just a smidge, again, behind behind
YouTube.
So I think, you know, definitely the
number one service globally and they
will consolidate that lead over all of
their rivals.
Great research, great recap Geetha
Ranganathan, we thank you from Bloomberg
Intelligence.
And that's it for this edition of
Bloomberg Technology.
What a weekend.
Yeah, it was an astonishing week.
And now earnings season is back upon us.
So much to recap.
You know where to find the podcast.
It is online on Apple Spotify and we
publish it to all the Bloomberg
platforms.
Thank you to the team in New York City.
Thank you to the team in San Francisco.
Happy weekend to all of you around the
world.
This is Bloomberg Technology.